Date: 2023-03-13 +46 705 86 94 08 staffan.bjornson@toor.se



# Staffan Björnson CV

One of my life mottos are:
" I rather take the time to do things well, than do things fast and have to do it twice."

# Test Automation Evangelist and automation workflows.

I have a diverse background in testing and QA for software and hardware. I have extensive experience and expertise in test automation. I have gained my skills by building test frameworks with a focus on mainlines and integration of automation into an agile software development life cycle. During my career, I have successfully identified test scenarios best suited for automation and the knowledge of when manual testing is more effective.

**Competencies in focus:** Test & verification, Automation, Test data management, Agile workflow, CI/CD, Linux/\*nix, Robot Framework, HSM, POS terminal verification

# **Assignment in focus**

**Test Automation Specialist** — Tele2 Working as a test automation specialist in quality refinement and requirement gathering. I implement and drive test automation and CI/CD initiatives in cooperation with the development teams.

# **Experience**

# **PwC**

2022 – Now Stockholm, Sweden

# **Test Specialist/Test Automator**

Developed and implemented an automated test framework for a customer a specific application that ran in an Azure DevOps environment.

#### **Tasks**

- Creating automated API tests
- Manage manual test suites
- Worked closely with developers to develop unit tests
- Developed an agile testing strategy
- Drove the agile way of working

#### **Test Automation**

Creating an automated test framework and rewriting manual tests to automated ones in close collaboration with the developers, BA, and PO. Introduced Robot Frameworks for a total automation suit in combination with Gherkin's "Given-When-Then" format. Technical know-how for the development of automated tests, primarily with Robot Frameworks and Python. Convert manual test suites, weed out old or ineffective tests, and find a possible way of approaching automation.

Test Automation, Test data management, Agile Workflow, Windows, DevOps Azure, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Git, Docker, API-testing,

#### Tele<sub>2</sub> AB

2019 – Dec 2022 Stockholm, Sweden

# **Test Automation Specialist**

Working as a test automation specialist in quality refinement and requirement gathering. I implement and drive test automation and CI/CD initiatives in cooperation with the development teams.

#### **Tasks**

- CI/CD implementation
- Test Strategy development
- Agile Work Flow implementation
- Education in agile methodology
- Manual to automation conversion

## **Test Automation Specialist**

As a member of the CI/CD team, the test specialist's job is to evaluate the development teams to be able to automate and become CI/CD. Creating specific test strategies for different development teams within Tele2 to facilitate and enhance the testing process.

## **Test Automation**

An important part of the assignment was to identify the needs of the development teams and find a framework that works for the teams when they need to automate. Part of the assignment was to hold courses in what you need to consider when implementing automation and potential pitfalls.

# Requirements analysis/Test management

I identify shortcomings in the quality process, an overall test the strategy was created for Tele2 that was implemented. Part of this work was to hold QA forums for test automation for mainly QA, PO and other stakeholders at Tele2 where we went through new innovations, how to must think, what is "best practice" etc.

Test Automation, Test data management, Agile Workflow, CI/CD, Linux/\*nix, Windows, DevOps Azure, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, RPA, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, API-testing,

# Kambi Group

**2018 – Oct 2019** Uppsala, Sweden

#### Tester/Test lead

Test lead in an autonomous agile team that delivered an odds calculation functions for sports betting.

#### **Tasks**

- Test manager
- Requirements in conjunction with stakeholders
- Manual System/exploratory testing
- Creating automated tests (UAT and regression)

## **Tester**

As a tester in an agile team, I created a test strategy and ran manual tests with a focus on exploratory testing. I also started a team project to automate our regression tests within the team, based on Python and Robot Framework that was integrated with our deploy pipeline.

Test Automation, Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Workflow, Linux/\*nix, Java, Kotlin, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, API-testing, Maven

# **Espland AB**

2015 – Nov 2018 Uppsala, Sweden

# Test lead/Jr Developer

As a tester and a developer for a TMS (POS-Terminal Management System) I manage testing and compliance with PCI DSS standards.

#### **Tasks**

- Software Testing
- Hardware Testing
- Compliance

- Java Development
- Support and Sales

#### **Technical Tester**

The role involved both working as a tester and junior developer within Java, in my role as test leader I had the main responsibility for ensuring that the tests of self-developed software including integrations to standard software have been carried out, through automated and manual tests in which I participated in the work with tests. When delivering software updates to the customer, I participated in the customer's work with tests of the product through support and direct efforts in the customer's test environment.

If necessary, I worked as a resource-reinforced CAPSAB team (Card and Payment Solution) with knowledge of verification and testing of payment terminals against both Swedish and international requirements.

Test Automation, Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Workflow, Linux/\*nix, Windows, Java, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, Elastic Search, API-testing, Maven

#### Verifone

**2011 - 2014** Uppsala, Sweden

# **Technical Tester/Test Environment Engineer**

As a software and hardware tester, I did manual tests but also built the test environments for our teams with integration with HMSs and third-party systems.

## **Tasks**

- Software Testing
- Hardware Testing
- Compliance
- POS-Terminal

- Test Environment management
- Agile workflows
- Support and Sales

#### **Technical Tester**

I did a manual acceptance test in close work with the developers (XP programming). We were the first team at Verifone to work in a SCRUM configuration so a lot of work went into finding a good and correct agile workflow.

At Verifone, I was responsible for their internal test environment from OS level up to test tools and integrations with HSM. Among other things, He helped build a system to automatically deploy OS and software to test environments.

Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Workflow, Linux/\*nix, Windows, Java, Vaadin, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, API-testing, Maven

# **Courses**

#### DevOps 2023 Learn CI/CD Process for Professionals and Teams

DevOps and CI/CD is a mindset. Practices of CI/CD for Agile Teams, including tips for remote workers -2023

# Elegant Automation Frameworks with Python and pyTest

Building a fast automation framework with minimal complexity that have actionable reporting using pyTest and Python. — 2023

## Linux Security and Hardening, The Practical Security Guide.

Security concepts and guidelines for hardening Linux system security. -2020

#### Robot Framework Test Automation (Level 1-2 & Jenkins CI)

Automate complex interactions across multiple web applications. Integrate Robot Framework tests into a Jenkins CI pipeline. — 2018, 2019

# **Skills**

# **Technical**

- Robot Frameworks
- pyTest
- Selenium
- Linux

- Linux Security
- Windows
- Azure DevOps
- Analytical Skills

- Test Automation
- Test Planning
- Agile Methodologies
- Agile Testing

- Scrum
- System Testing
- Python

- Jenkins
- Red Hat Satellite
- FreeIPA

- Payment Gateways
- Selenium

# Language

- Swedish
- English

# **Driving license**

- A Motorcycle
- B Car

# **Social**





**GitHub** github.com/StaffanOB/



Toor.se www.toor.se/